Tom Walsh - hello@tmwlsh.co.uk - Linkedin

Profile:

I've been interested in building online experiences since I was 9 years old. I played an online game that allowed you to add code snippets to your profile to make them more interactive - and that was it, I was hooked. Since then I've worked for a range of businesses, from small startups to global agencies and brands. A project that always springs to mind when I think about my career is a global design system that I was involved with. It was my job to maintain and develop the design system. At one point the system was used in over 150 countries and was seen by millions of people every day. My passion lies in creating intuitive customer experiences. If our clients' customers enjoy using our websites, then I'm happy.

Key Skills: HTML, CSS, SCSS, LESS, Tailwind, Javascript, React, React Hooks, State, Gatsby, NextJS, Vue, Nuxt, Shopify, Liquid, Shopify API, Shopify Theme Kit, Headless CMS', Wordpress, Statamic, Prismic, Figma, Git, UI animations, Git, Git Flow.

Experience:

Onstate: Oct 2023 – Present | Senior Designer & Shopify Developer

I joined Onstate and immediately got thrown in at the deep end on a large scale build for a multinational book reselling company. There were a lot of third-party api integrations, so my skills as a JavaScript developer came in very handy. We have a range of clients in various industries including; Healthcare, Fashion, Beauty, FMCG brands, etc. I've built custom solutions including subscription models, build-a-box functionality, added product customization tools, and worked with a range of different apps to meet our clients requirements. Another area that I've been heavily involved in is CRO, A/B testing and growth. I've helped implement strategies that have increased our clients' CVR, AOV and repeat customer rates considerably. Some notable clients that I've worked with include Mamas & Papas, World of Books, ACAI outdoors, Prickle Plants, Crockett & Jones and Watch Gecko.

Self Employed: Jul 2021 - Oct 2023 | Senior Javascript Developer

I was lucky enough to work for myself between 2021 and 2023. During that time I contracted for many different businesses to complete a range of tasks - most of which involved building user interfaces that paired up with enterprise CMS' such as Sitecore. I enjoyed the challenge of managing my own workload as well as sourcing work, completing invoices and managing the day to day running of a business. It gave me the opportunity to work closely with end clients which helped develop my communication skills.

Some notable clients that I worked with during that time were; TGI Fridays, Giantx gaming, Rowse Honey and Biffa Bins.

Home Agency: May 2019 - Apr 2021 | Javascript Developer

I thoroughly enjoyed my time at Home Agency. I was given the opportunity to maintain a global design system that was used by millions of users every day. It was my responsibility to communicate with the design team, create descriptive tasks for developers, while also being deeply involved with the development of new features and functionality. I had a great manager at Home Agency who pushed me, and helped me develop as a developer. I still keep in touch with him now.

As well as the design system, I was involved with the development of many other websites, including some which utilised the Headless approach by combining a React frontend (usually built in Gatsby or Nextjs) and a Headless CMS such as Wordpress, Prismic or contentful.

Digitronix: May 2019 - Apr 2021 | Full Stack Developer

During my time at Digitronix I built 8 websites from scratch using a self developed Wordpress starter theme, as well as maintaining a long list of legacy websites. I was able to own the full process from receiving the design files, to setting up production and staging environments, to developing the website to deployments. I learnt a lot about server configuration, cloudflare, building reusable components and project planning.

Blueclaw: Jun 2017 - May 2018 | Front End Developer

My time at Blueclaw was exceptionally fast paced. We built Javascript based content campaigns mainly for gambling and gaming clients. We built interactive experiences that were 'share-worthy' and gained lots of attention from the press. A particular project that I was proud to have been a part of was a GG generator - a quiz that based on users answers, suggested a horse for the user to bet on at the Grand National. It got national coverage in a long list of well known publications including the BBC, Sky Sports, The Daily Mail and many more.

Most projects that we built used Vue on the front end and JSON data rather than a conventional CMS. This was often due to the short project timelines.

I really enjoyed my time at Blueclaw as it opened my eyes to different ways of using Javascript to manipulate and organise data.

Brass Agency: Mar 2016 - Jun 2017 | Junior Full Stack Developer

My time at Brass will be looked back on fondly. It was my first experience of the fast paced agency life that I have come to know and love. I was exposed to working with CMS', building templates based on designs and deploying work through systems such as DeployHQ.

Most of our websites were Wordpress based, but some used Drupal. They all used HTML and SCSS on the frontend, as well as vanilla JS.

Formisimo: Apr 2015 - Mar 2016 | Junior Designer

My first job out of university was at a CRO startup called Formisimo based in Manchester. My job was to design whitepapers, blog articles, website assets and occasionally web pages. The office vibe was fantastic; table football, full snack cupboards and daily mindfulness walks. I really enjoyed my time there, but when the opportunity to join a fast paced agency showed itself, I couldn't resist.

Education:

- University 2:1 Graphic Design
- Code in the Dark Champion 2018

Interests: I enjoy running & gorge walking in the Lake District, Northern Lights chasing, travelling, dog walking and camping. Being outdoors generally brings me peace, clarity and happiness.